Ravi Teja Ponnuri Venkata

+1 647-513-5990

rvitejapv@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Business Analyst in Data Migration with an experience of working in the **Telecom Domain**. Skilled in Informatica Power Center, Developer, Oracle, Data Migration, Transformation Projects, ETL- DWH projects. Experienced in Telecom software development and quality teams in data/system migration projects in the BSS stack.

Work Experience

Business Analyst – Data Migration

Amdocs Development Centre India LLP

Jul 2018 - Apr 2021

- Data Migration Software development covering assignments in Requirement Scoping -Gathering from clients, Business and System Analysts, Mapping Business workflows with system workflows, Software Development & Unit testing.
- Lead Scrum meetings and weekly triage meetings and conducted code and requirement reviews with peers, cross teams and customer.
- Business Analysis and Data Modelling to migrate the Telefonica Customer and Usage/Billing data into Amdocs Billing and CRM applications.
- Analysis of reference data which is shared by downstream applications and validating the consistency for every Product which is implemented in CRM, OMS and ABP.
- Expertise in working with Extraction, Transformation and loading data, Debugging mappings or sessions and performance tuning of Informatica and SQL Queries.
- Implemented a data cut process utility by uniquely mapping and identification of each customer or account by using unique ASCII value for subset cut.
- Effectively handled the Billing module zoning distribution of data in Migration code by proper sequence handling mechanism.
- Handled multiple migration production rollouts for a South American Telecom Provider migrating millions of postpaid customers.
- Solution design of migration code of various modules of Amdocs Billing product, CRM and OMS modules.
- Strong Informatica development experience working on Informatica Designer Components -Source Analyzer, Mapping Designer, Transformation Developer, Workflow Manager and Workflow Monitor.

Associate Consultant

May 2016 - Jul 2018

Virtusa Consulting Services Ltd.

- Extensively used ETL methodology for developing and supporting data extraction, transformations and loading process, in a corporate-wide-ETL Solution using Informatica.
- Implemented performance tuning logic on targets, sources, mappings, sessions to provide maximum efficiency and performance, Creating new mappings and workflows with business logic.
- Analyzing, Designing, Development, Unit Testing and Deployment of the Informatica and SQL enhancements.
- Developed and modified SQL and PL/SQL code to make new enhancements or resolve problems, as per customer requirements. Involved in all phases of SDLC from requirement gathering, design, development, testing, Production, user training and support for production

environment. Created new mapping designs using various tools in Informatica Designer like Source Analyzer, Warehouse Designer, Mapplet Designer and Mapping Designer. Developed the mappings using needed Transformations in Informatica tool according to technical specifications

- Created complex mappings that involved the implementation of Business Logic to load data into the staging area.
- · Used Informatica reusability at various levels of development.
- Developed mappings/sessions using Informatica Power Center 9.6 for data loading.
- Performed data manipulations using various Informatica Transformations like Filter, Expression, Lookup (Connected and Lin-connected), Aggregate, Update Strategy,
- Normalizer, Joiner, Router, Sorter and Union.
- Developed Workflows using task developer, Worklet designer and workflow designer in Workflow manager and monitored the results using workflow monitor.
- · Building Reports according to user requirements.
- Implemented slowly changing dimension methodology for accessing the full history of accounts.
- Write Shell script running workflows in the UNIX environment.
- · Optimizing performance tuning at source, target, mapping and session level
- Lead daily scrum and weekly status meetings and conducting internal and external reviews as well as formal walk through among various teams and documenting the proceedings.

Junior Software Engineer

Aug 2013 - May 2016

Tech Mahindra

- Developed and executed detailed ETL related functional, performance, integration and regression test cases, and documentation.
- Analyze and understand the functional ETL workflows developed.
- · Strong in ETL data validation using Informatica.
- Informatica / Datastage ETL environments
- Quality Management Knowledge of quality management methods, tools and techniques.
- Reviewed database business and functional requirements, reviewed mapping transformations.
- Worked with Program Managers, Requirement Analysts, Mappers, Developers, and other testers to resolve issues with requirements/mapping transformations
- · Created Test Plans and test scripts, executed test scripts, and wrote Test Report.
- Extensively used SQL queries for data validation and backend testing.
- Validating the data files from the source to make sure correct data has been captured to be loaded to target tables.
- Preparation of Test Cases based on ETL Specification Document, Use Cases, Low-Level Design document.
- Played a crucial role in the creation and testing of designed scalable, reusable, and low maintenance ETL templates.

Education

Postgraduate Certificate
Data Analytics for Business Decision Making (Jan 2021 – Aug 21*)
Durham College, Canada

Bachelor of Science

Osmania University, India Computer Science

Skills

- ETL
- Informatica Power Centre
- Informatica Developer
- Data Migration
- Data Transformation
- Exploratory Data Analysis and Mining
- Oracle
- UNIX
- PL-SQL
- Perl
- Server-side Scripting
- Java
- Microsoft Power BI
- Tableau
- Microsoft Suite

Professional Credentials

- International Software Testing Qualifications Board (ISTQB) Certification
- · Oracle Certification

Languages

English - Full Professional Proficiency Hindi - Full Professional Proficiency Telugu – Native or Bilingual Proficiency